<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Kitchener\'s Map</string>
    <string name="about_heading_1">About this app</string>
    <string name="about_paragraph_1">In 1885, Horatio Herbert Kitchener’s map of Cyprus, which was the result of the
        first scientific survey of the island, was published in London by Edward Stanford of 55 Charing Cross Road, SW.
    </string>
    <string name="about_paragraph_2">The map was printed in 16 sheets and became a cartographic model up to the middle
        of the 20th century. This map, of pivotal importance for the cartography of Cyprus, contains a multitude of
        significant information regarding the geography, history and culture of the island. Even today, much of this
        data requires attentive research by the scientific community.
    </string>
    <string name="about_paragraph_3">This web application for exploring Kitchener’s survey was developed on the basis of
        Sylvia Ioannou Foundation particular interest in the historic cartography of Cyprus, as well as the interest of
        the Department of Geography Department of the Harokopio University concerning the scientific approach to similar
        topics.
    </string>
    <string name="about_paragraph_4">On the one hand, the application constitutes a digital repository of the original
        map and offers online access to researchers worldwide. On the other hand, thanks to the database created, where
        all the information found on Kitchener’s map is registered and categorised, the user is able to search for
        specific points or entire fields of interest (for example, from a particular spring to the whole hydrographic
        network; from a single village to all settlements per religion of population, etc.). Furthermore, through the
        option to connect with modern background basemaps, it facilitates the comparison of the information provided by
        Kitchener with respective modern data. Along with its obvious practicality related to the cartography,
        geography, history and culture of Cyprus, this application aspires to become a starting point for
        interdisciplinary cooperation and to provide the necessary technical expertise for the development of similar
        research projects in the future.
    </string>
    <string name="about_heading_2">Kitchener\'s survey of Cyprus</string>
    <string name="about_paragraph_5">During the Ottoman Empire’s dominance, the Ottoman Land Code was enacted in Cyprus.
        This was a cadastre in which all land acquisition deeds and transactions were recorded by means of draft
        drawings and descriptions in Turkish. When Cyprus became a British protectorate in 1878, the translation of the
        Land Code – an extremely time consuming process – and the compilation of a modern map were deemed necessary to
        facilitate the administration and development of the island.
    </string>
    <string name="about_paragraph_6">In order to map the new protectorate of the British Empire, the 28-year old army
        surveyor and Foreign Office delegate Horatio Herbert Kitchener met with the British High Commissioner, Sir
        Garnet Wolseley, at the dependency of the Kykkos Monastery just outside Nicosia on 15 September 1878. Wolseley
        needed a survey for the next financial year, while Kitchener envisioned a map that would ‘be a model of its
        kind, and future scholars and archaeologists would be permanently in his debt’. The two men came to a rift, and
        in the next year the triangulation works were abandoned due to lack of resources. In 1880, Sir Robert Biddulph,
        who succeeded Wolseley as High Commissioner of the island, invited Kitchener back. Kitchener brought along
        George Gordon Hake, a somewhat controversial figure, to collect and sell findings from excavations in Kourion
        and Salamina to help fund the island’s survey. Those findings were not significant, as Luigi Palma di Cesnola
        had been there before. Finally, everything collected was catalogued in an amateur manner and scattered around
        British museums. While in Cyprus, Kitchener was also responsible for the organisation and reformation of the
        Land Registry as a just and rational means of land acquisition and crop taxing throughout the island.
    </string>
    <string name="about_paragraph_7">By 1883, the survey was completed and the Land Registry was organised. In 1885, the
        map publisher Edward Stanford promoted the map as follows:
    </string>
    <string name="about_paragraph_8">It has been engraved on [...] copper plates [...] when mounted together as one Map
        measuring 12 feet 6 inches by 7 feet [...] It shews the Districts and Sub-districts [...] the Roads that have
        been constructed, and the Telegraph Lines erected [...] the Vineyards and Forests of Fir and other trees; block
        plans of the Towns and Villages, distinguishing Moslem and Christian Villages; gives the Greek and Turkish
        names, and the identification of Ancient Sites, in distinct types. Aqueducts, Springs, Wells, Monasteries,
        Ruins, and other particulars are engraved. Heights of Hills and Mountains, Towns and Villages, above the level
        of the Sea, are also pretty generally supplied, and Mile-stones, with the mileage written against them, engraved
        so far as they had been erected at the moment of final revision. [...] It is the first Survey ever executed of
        this interesting Island, and is in itself a noble result of the English Occupation.
    </string>
    <string name="about_paragraph_9">The question posed by the Sylvia Ioannou Foundation to the Department of Geography
        of the Harokopio University was whether all claims by Stanford were true and how close Kitchener actually came
        to his vision.
    </string>
    <string name="about_paragraph_10">After leaving Cyprus, Kitchener went on with his military career. His renowned
        victories in the Sudan and in South Africa earned him the title of Viscount Kitchener, but also the nickname
        ‘Soulless Commander’. In 1914, on the verge of Word World I and while Kitchener was Commander-in-Chief in India,
        Prime Minister Herbert Asquith asked him to return to England in order to become Secretary of State for War.
        Kitchener’s reputation and influence were so great that, among a total of 2,675,149 volunteers who enlisted
        during all four years of the Great War, 462,901 of those volunteers alone enlisted in September 1914, when the
        famous recruitment poster with his picture appeared.
    </string>
    <string name="menu_item_opacity_slider">Background Basemaps</string>
    <string name="menu_item_feedback">Feedback</string>
    <string name="menu_item_about_the_application">About this app</string>
    <string name="menu_item_types_of_places">Map layers</string>
    <string name="select_language">Language:</string>
    <string name="title_activity_maps">Kitchener\'s Map</string>
    <string name="feedback_comment_label">Comment:</string>
    <string name="feedback_takePhoto_button">Take Photo</string>
    <string name="feedback_sendMail_button">Send Email</string>
    <string name="feedBackInstuctions_text">This application lets you send us a location with your own comment and
        photo. Just press on the map for two seconds and then press on the marker\'s info window.
    </string>
    <string name="types_of_places_coffee_shops">Coffee Shops</string>
    <string name="types_of_places_banks">Banks</string>
    <string name="types_of_places_lodging">Lodging</string>
    <string name="types_of_places_museum">Museums</string>
    <string name="types_of_places_political">Political</string>
    <string name="types_of_places_hospitals">Hospitals</string>
    <string name="types_of_places_library">Libraries</string>
    <string name="types_of_places_restaurant">Restaurants</string>
    <string name="types_of_places_supermarket">Supermarkets</string>
    <string name="menu_item_search">Search for a place</string>
    <string name="search_hint">Enter search term</string>
    <string name="search_subtitle">Please type at least 3 characters</string>
    <string name="search_result_subtitle">$ results found</string>
    <string name="name">Name</string>
    <string name="name_in_greek">Name in Greek:</string>
    <string name="name_in_english">Name in English:</string>
    <string name="second_name">Second name:</string>
    <string name="district">District:</string>

</resources>